Sherilyn Koshy

New York, NY | (408) 394-8828 | sherilyn.koshy@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Summary

Full-stack software developer with a multidisplinary background in operations, corporate finance, risk management, and 7+ years of FinTech experience. Driven to create meaningful impact with dynamic solutions that promote human flourishing.

Projects

- Project
- Project
- Project

Skills

Languages & Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, MongoDB / Mongoose, Express, PostgreSQL, Python, Django, REST APIs

Tools: Salesforce.com CRM, Atlassian Confluence & Jira, Kibana, Sisense, SQL, Git / GitHub

Experience

Risk Analyst

July 2019 - October 2022

Plaid, New York, NY

- Mitigated security risks to the consumer ecosystem by monitoring all API traffic and identifying & blocking
 potential account takeover fraud; acted as first responder as part of a monthly on-call rotation
- Conducted risk assessments on over 1000 prospective customers, ranging from startup to enterprise
- Developed operational workflows and wrote detailed policies & procedures for regulatory programs in the US and Europe
- Collaborated cross-functionally with Engineering, GTM, Legal, and Product teams

Compliance Analyst

February 2018 - July 2019

Upstart, San Carlos, CA

- Conducted fair lending analyses using Bayesian Improved Surname Geocoding (BISG) proxy methodology
- Monitored customer complaints program and produced monthly reports for various bank partners
- Managed new hire and annual compliance training program for all employees

Treasury Analyst

May 2016 - February 2018

LendingClub, San Francisco, CA

- Performed daily reconciliations of system and cash transactions using the Kyriba Treasury Management System and Excel
- Prepared reports for Audit and Compliance teams using SQL to retrieve data

Operations Associate

September 2015 - March 2016

Upstart (contract), San Carlos, CA

- Maintained client databases and monitored operational metrics using Salesforce.com technology
- Generated monthly reports on consumer complaints and presented analyses to streamline underwriting and reporting procedures and ensure compliance with applicable regulations
- Generated Suspicious Activity Reports for fraudulent loan applications and conducted analyses on common fraud characteristics

Education

General Assembly, New York, NY University of California, Irvine, Irvine, CA